Still together, still lost.
Madagascar: Escape 2 Africa is a adventure, animation,
comedy film directed by Eric Darnell.
Alex, Marty, and other zoo animals find a way to escape from
Madagascar when the penguins reassemble a wrecked airplane.
The precariously repaired craft stays airborne just long
enough to make it to the African continent.
There the New Yorkers encounter members of their own species for the first time.
Africa proves to be a wild place, but Alex and company wonder
if it is better than their Central Park home.
Alex (voice), played by Ben Stiller.
Marty / Additional Zebras (voice), played by Chris Rock.
Melman (voice), played by David Schwimmer.
Gloria (voice), played by Jada Pinkett Smith.
Julien (voice), played by Sacha Baron Cohen.
Maurice (voice), played by Cedric the Entertainer.
Madagascar: Escape 2 Africa (also known as Madagascar 2: Escape to Africa) is a 2008 American animated adventure
comedy film directed by Eric Darnell and Tom McGrath and written by  Etan Cohen, Darnell and McGrath.
The second installment in the Madagascar film series, following the
2005 film, it was produced by DreamWorks Animation SKG.
Ben Stiller, Chris Rock, David Schwimmer, Jada Pinkett Smith, Sacha Baron Cohen, Cedric the Entertainer, Andy Richter, Elisa Gabrielli, McGrath, Chris Miller, Christopher
Knights, and Conrad Vernon reprise their roles from the first film, joined by new cast members Bernie Mac, Alec Baldwin, Sherri Shepherd, and will.i.am.
In the film, the main characters, a party of animals from the Central Park Zoo whose adventures have taken them to Madagascar find
themselves in the African savannas, where they meet others of their species and where Alex the lion reunites with his parents.
The film, like its predecessor, has a score composed by Hans Zimmer.
Singer will.i.am contributed five songs to the soundtrack.
Released by Paramount Pictures on November 7, 2008, Madagascar: Escape 2 Africa received generally positive reviews from critics,
who praised its characters, humor and animation, while also considering it an improvement over its predecessor.
It grossed $604 million on a $150 million budget, making it
the sixth highest-grossing film of 2008.
It was dedicated to Bernie Mac, who died before the film's release.
A sequel, Madagascar 3: Europe's Most Wanted, was released in 2012.
The film explores themes of dance, friendship, jealousy, airplane, africa.
The tone is lighthearted.